Aleksandar Stipan

Germany

astipan@gmail.com

As a self-taught programmer, my enthusiasm lies in data analysis, backend development and automation. I'm excited to apply my analytical mindset to projects requiring technical expertise, creative problem-solving and automation solutions. Additionally, I remain open to opportunities for growth, collaboration and addressing real-world challenges with my skill set.

Work Experience

Coding

10/2022 to Present

- Self-taught programmer with a strong commitment to learning and excelling in data analysis and backend development.

Discretionary Trader

10/2017 to Present

Freelance

- Price action trader specializing in index futures market (MNQ, MES) and crypto derivatives.

CEO and Owner

08/2014 to 01/2018

M and M d.o.o

Varazdin

- Managed a small company focused on buying and selling wood goods for sawmills and furniture factories.
- Oversaw daily business operations, negotiated with new suppliers, and closed deals.

Key Account

05/2014 to 09/2014

Goclick d.o.o.

Zagreb

- Counseled and searched for business partners, directed online marketing strategies (Web sites, Ad Words, Google display net, Facebook, Twitter, YouTube).
- Collaborated as a Google partner to improve marketing campaigns.

Complaints - Back Office Work

02/2014 to 03/2014

Hrvatski Telekom

Zagreb

- Analyzed and resolved oral and written complaints from mobile services consumers.
- Implemented procedures to prevent future mistakes and communicated with users to uphold corporate values.

Customer Service Agent

04/2013 to 02/2014

Hrvatski Telekom

Zagreb

- Provided customer care, advertised and sold services, and advised users on balancing service and price.
- Possessed a strong technical background in fixed and mobile services.

Skills

Python Nginx
Go Git
Django Jenkins
Flask GitHub

Postman API GitHub Actions

SQL CI/CD
PostgreSQL DevOps
FastAPI Price action
Pandas Futures Trading

Docker Cryptocurrency Trading

Linux Public Relations

Education

University of Zagreb Centre for Croatian Studies

Master's

Mag.comm, Public Relations

Zagreb

2011 to 2014

Faculty of Philosophy of The Society of Jesus in Zagreb

Bachelor's

univ. bacc. phil., Philosophy

Zagreb

2008 to 2011

Archdiocesan Classical Gymnasium

High school or equivalent

Zagreb

2004 to 2018